

Personal Website gordeev.page

vanGordeev

Curriculum Vitae

General Information

Full Name: Ivan Sergeevich Gordeev

Sex: Male

Date of Birth: 21th July 1996

Place of Birth: Russia, Moscow oblast, Taldom

Nationality: Russian Marital Status: Married



Work Experience

Researcher 2023 - ...

Joint Institute for Nuclear Research

Researcher at the Laboratory of Radiation Biology. Radiation Research Department of the base facilities. Joint Institute for Nuclear Research (Dubna,

Russia)





2020 – 2023 Junior Researcher

Joint Institute for Nuclear Research

Junior Researcher at the Laboratory of Radiation Biology. Section of Radiation Research. Research group for studying radiation fields of JINR basic facilities and environment. Joint Institute for Nuclear Research (Dubna,

Russia)



2017-2020 Laboratory Assistant

Joint Institute for Nuclear Research

Laboratory Assistant at the Laboratory of Radiation Biology. Section of Radiation Research. Research group for studying radiation fields of JINR basic facilities and environment. Joint Institute for Nuclear Research (Dubna,

Russia)



Languages Russian ★★★★ English ★★★★

Education

2020 – 2024 **PhD Student**

Dubna State University

Dubna State University. Engineering and Physics Institute. Department of Fundamental problems of microworld physics (Dubna, Russia)

Major: Physics and astronomy

GPA: 5.00/5.00

2018-2020 MSc (with honours) in Physics

Dubna State University

Dubna State University. Department of Biophysics. Faculty of Natural and

Engineering Sciences (Dubna, Russia)

Specialization: Radiation Biophysics and Astrobiology

Thesis title: "Monte Carlo Simulation of Radiation Fields Inside the Spacecraft and Calculation of Astronaut Doses on the Earth-Mars Flight"

GPA: 5.00/5.00

2014-2018 BSc (with honours) in Physics

Dubna State University

Dubna State University. Department of Biophysics. Faculty of Natural and

Engineering Sciences (Dubna, Russia)

Specialization: Human and Environmental Radiation Safety

Thesis title: "Simulation of Radiation Fields Inside Spacecraft in the

Earth's Environment" **GPA:** 4.95/5.00

Activities & Awards

24-28.10.22 Scientific conference

Joint Institute for Nuclear Research

Participation in the XXVI International Scientific Conference of Young Scientists and Specialists (Dubna, Russia). Topic of report: "A new type of ground-based simulator of inner radiation field of a spacecraft in deep space"

Results: Certificate of Attendance

21.9.21 Online videoconference

GSI Helmholtz Center for Heavy Ion Research

Participation in the ESA-FAIR Space Radiation Summer School special videoconference (Darmstadt, Germany)

Results: Certificate of Attendance

19-22.7.21 **Online tutorial**

Japan Atomic Energy Agency (JAEA)

Participation in the advanced course on PHITS (Tokai, Japan)

Results: Certificate of Attendance

1-5.2.21 Online tutorial

Japan Atomic Energy Agency (JAEA)

Participation in the basic course on PHITS (Tokai, Japan)

Results: Certificate of Attendance

5-16.10.20 Online training

The European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN)

Attended the FLUKA Beginners' Online Training. Switzerland, Meyrin.

Results: Certificate of Attendance

17.4.20 Scientific-practical conference

Dubna State University

Participation in the XXVII annual regional scientific-practical conference for students, postgraduates and young specialists at Dubna State University with the topic of report: "Calculation of radiation fields during the operation of the Booster and Nuclotron of the NICA complex". Russia, Dubna

Results: Best Student Presentation Award of the "Radiation Biophysics and Astrobiology" subsection

15-16.4.19 Scientific-practical conference

Dubna State University

Participation in the XXVI annual regional scientific-practical conference of students, postgraduates and young specialists at Dubna State University with the topic of report: "Calculation of the radiation fields from the GCR inside the spacecraft during interplanetary flights". Russia, Dubna

Results: Best Student Presentation Award

3.12.18 Scientific-popular student conference

Dubna State University

Participation in the scientific-popular student conference in English: "Universe of Science. Challenges and Solutions" at Dubna State University with the topic of report: "Breaking the Wall of Cosmic Radiation using Particle Accelerator"

Results: Best Student Presentation Award and nomination for "The Best Communicative Skills and Best Presentation"

22.10.18 Competition

Dubna State University

Participant of the "Best students of the Dubna State University" competition **Results:** Best Student of the Dubna State University Award

17-19.10.18 International Conference

International Conference Hall in Dubna

Participant of the meeting of the International Conference "Modern Problems of Space Radiobiology and Astrobiology"

Results: Co-author of the conference report: "Modeling Radiation Fields Inside Spacecraft at JINR's Nuclotron"

23.7-13.9.18 Summer Student Program

GSI Helmholtz Center for Heavy Ion Research

Participation in the HGS-HIRe Summer Student Program 2018 at GSI. Germany, Darmstadt

Results: Skills received: in using MC transport code FLUKA, in work with ROOT framework. The skills of scientific writing and presentation, as well as teamwork skills and communication in a foreign language were improved. Attended a number of lectures on various fields of physics. Got acquainted with the main facilities of the GSI (UNILAC, ESR, HADES, HILITE) and the FAIR project. A report on the work in the research group was written: "Comparison of MCNPX, GEANT4 and FLUKA Simulations of the Radiation Situation Inside a Spacecraft in Deep Space", and a presentation was made on the closing section. The report is published in the proceedings of the 2018 HGS-HIRe Summer Student Program

17.4.18 Scientific-practical conference

Dubna State University

Participation in the XXV annual regional scientific-practical conference of students, postgraduates and young specialists at Dubna State University with the topic of report: "Simulation of Radiation Fields Inside Spacecraft in the Earth's Environment". Russia. Dubna

Results: Publication in the conference proceedings, certificate of participation

26.1-5.2.18 Personnel exchange program (Winter School)

Kindai University

Participation in the personnel exchange program "Monodukuri Engineer in Japan and Russia" winter student school at Kindai University. Japan, Osaka **Results:** Communication skills in a foreign language were improved. Got acquainted with Japanese culture, manufactory and Monodukuri technique

2.10.17 **Pitch competition** Visit Centre of Joint Institute for Nuclear Research (JINR)
Participation in the "Falling Walls Lab Dubna", international Lab season stage at Joint Institute for Nuclear Research. Russia, Dubna

Results: Certificate of participation

30.3.17 **Scientific-practical conference**

Dubna State University

Participation in the XXIV annual regional scientific-practical conference of students, postgraduates and young specialists at Dubna State University with the topic of report: "Simulation of Radiation Fields Inside Spacecraft". Russia, Dubna

Results: Publication in the conference proceedings, certificate of participation

16.12.16 Scientific-popular student conference

Dubna State University

Participation in the scientific-popular student conference in English "Discovering the Mysteries of Science" at Dubna State University with the topic of report: "Feynman Diagrams". Russia, Dubna

Results: Second Best Presentation Award and nomination for the "Best Pronunciation"

Articles

1. I.S. Gordeev & G.N. Timoshenko

Physics of Particles and Nuclei Letters, vol. 19, pp. 402-407 (2022)

"Albedo of Neutrons of Relativistic Energies"

DOI: 10.1134/S1547477122040136

2. G.N. Timoshenko & I.S. Gordeev

Physics and Technique of Accelerators, vol. 19, pp. 123-128 (2022)

"Prediction of Radiation Environment around NICA Complex"

DOI: 10.1134/S1547477122020042

3. G.N. Timoshenko & I.S. Gordeev

Radiobiology, Ecology and Nuclear Medicine, vol. 18, pp. 799-805 (2021)

"Reference Radiation Field for GCR Chronic Exposure Simulation"

DOI: 10.1134/S1547477121070128

4. I.S. Gordeev & G.N. Timoshenko

Life Sciences in Space Research, vol. 30, pp. 66-71 (2021)

"A new type of ground-based simulator of radiation field inside a spacecraft in deep space"

DOI: 10.1016/j.lssr.2021.05.002

5. G.N. Timoshenko & I.S. Gordeev

Planetary and Space Science, vol. 199 (2021)

"Computation of linear energy transfer of space radiation in biological tissue analog"

DOI: 10.1016/j.pss.2021.105190

6. G.N. Timoshenko & I.S. Gordeev

Physics of Particles and Nuclei Letters, vol. 17, n. 7, pp. 951 – 957 (2020)

"Calculating the Linear Energy Transfer Distribution in Radiobiological Experiments on the U400M Cyclotron"

DOI: 10.1134/S1547477120070055

7. G.N. Timoshenko & I.S. Gordeev

Physics of Particles and Nuclei, vol. 51, n. 5, pp. 988-993 (2020)

"Estimation of the Astronaut's Doses inside the Spacecraft Habitable Module in Deep Space"

DOI: 10.1134/S106377962005007X

8. G.N. Timoshenko & <u>I.S. Gordeev</u>

Physics of Particles and Nuclei Letters, vol. 17, n. 3, pp. 379-388 (2020)

"Forecasting Radiation Environment around the NICA Booster"

DOI: 10.1134/S1547477120030152

9. G.N. Timoshenko & I.S. Gordeev

Journal of Astrophysics and Astronomy, vol. 41 (2020)

"Simulation of radiation field inside interplanetary spacecraft"

DOI: 10.1007/s12036-020-9620-3

10. G.N. Timoshenko, A.R. Krylov, M. Paraipan, I.S. Gordeev

Radiation Measurements, vol. 107, pp. 27-32 (2017)

"Particle Accelerator-Based Simulation of the Radiation Environment on Board Spacecraft for Manned Interplanetary Missions"

DOI: 10.1016/j.radmeas.2017.10.006

OS Knowledge

Windows ★★★★

Preprints

1. I. S. Gordeev, A. N. Bugay

Preprint of the Joint Institute for Nuclear Research [E11-2024-17] (2024) "Computer modeling of a new type galactic cosmic rays simulator"

Programming

Python **** Bash ★★★★★ Fortran ★★★★★ C++ **** 2. Ivan Gordeev

ArXiv e-prints [cs.HC, hep-ex] (2020)

"FitsGeo – Python package for PHITS geometry development and visualization" arXiv:2008.03298

Software in Use

Alma Mater



Ubuntu OS: FLUKA+Flair, PHITS, GEANT4, ROOT, GnuPlot, Jupyter Notebook, LATEX, GIMP, Inkscape, PyCharm, Visual Studio Code, Git

Windows OS: Origin, Microsoft Office applications, Mathcad, Autodesk Inventor, Auto-CAD, Photoshop

Hobbies

Computer modeling, Arduino-based modeling, DIY, sport (basketball, volleyball and American football), design and architecture.

About me



JOINT INSTITUTE FOR **NUCLEAR RESEARCH**

One of my favorite physicists is Richard Feynman and I really like one of his famous quotes: "What I Cannot Create, I Do Not Understand". I perceive this expression as my credo. And I interpret it in the way that if you can't "create" something, no matter how: in your mind, or in real life - performing an experiment, then you can't understand it properly.

To understand something better you always need to invent new approaches and develop new models describing actual problem. After a long and persistent reflection and attempts to solve the problem a solution comes.

Let's create in order to understand!